const que = [
    {
        question: "How does Social Scientists define an Environment",
        answer: "According to Social Scientists, an environment is defined as the aggregate of all internal and external conditions affecting the existence, growth and welfare of organisms. (Okafor, 1991 page 65)",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "According to Webster Dictionary, define an Environment",
        answer: "According to Webster Dictionary, an environment is the totality of all external conditions affecting the life and development of organisms whether on land, air or water.",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "According to (Sada, 1988, page 27), what is an Environment?",
        answer: "Environment is a system in which the living organisms interact with the physical elements.",
        coursecode: 201
    },, 
    {
        question: "Systems of Enviroment can be called",
        answer: "An ECOSYSTEM or PRINCIPLES of ENVIRONMENTAL UNITY.",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "What is an Ecosystem?",
        answer: "An ecosystem is a network or community of individuals that is arranged into a self-organized and complex hierarchy of patterns and processes, where it creates a bio-physical feedback between a living (biotic) and non-living (abiotic)",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "How are the Ecosystem sustained?",
        answer: "They are sustained by the Biodiversity within them.",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "According to Phil Eze, what is an Ecosystem?",
        answer: "According to (Phil Eze, 2009 page 291), an Ecosystem is defined as a total surroundings of man including air, water, plants, natural resources, fauna, flora and humans including their interactions.",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "Who categorized Environment into several groups?",
        answer: "(Orogwu 1994, page 3) categorized an environment into several groups, namely: Biological Environment, Social Environment, Health Environment, Workplace Environment.",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "Who else further categorized an Environment?",
        answer: "Hezeazy, added the following environments :- Legal Environment, Technological Environment, Economic Environment and Political Environment.",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "What is considered Development in an environment?",
        answer: "Development is the mystery of an environment, which implies new ideas, observation, changes in lifestyle which affects the totality of human intellectual and physical activities.",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "What is a Social Structure?",
        answer: "Social Structure refers to the organized sets of social institutions and patterns of relationship that together compose a society.",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "Define a Society.",
        answer: "It is derived from the latin word SOCIETAS, which simply means COMPANIONSHIP / FRIENDSHIP. It refers to a large group of people that share and are expected to abide by laws within the same territory, social structure and also share a common culture. It may also be defined as the totality of social relationships among organised group of human beings",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "List the types of Society.",
        answer: "Pre-Industrial, Industrial & Post-Industrial",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "List the features of a Pre-Industrial Society.",
        answer: `
        1. They were small.  
        2. They were rural and largely dependent on local tools and resources.`,
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "Pre-Industrial society is further sub-divided into three which are:-",
        answer: `
        I. Hunting and Gathering Society:- They relied on the society for survival.  
        II. Pastoral and Herding Society :- This society relied on the domestication of animals.  
        III. Horticutural Society :- It was based on the capacity of people to grow and cultivate crops.`,
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "What are Values?",
        answer: "Values are ideas held by individuals or groups about what is desirable, proper, good or bad. It differs from society to society.",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "What are Norms?",
        answer: "Norms are defined as correct or proper forms of behaviour. They can also be referred to as specific prescriptions about how individuals ought to behave to be consistent with the values of the contemporary society.",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "What are the Forms of Norms?",
        answer: `
        I. FOLKWAYS :- This type of norms do not attract too much punishment when they are broken.  
        II. MORES :- are the norms in the society that breaking them attracts severe punishments.`,
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "What are Social Institutions?",
        answer: "They refer to a system of behaviourial and relationship patterns that are closely interwoven and enduring, and functions across an entire society.",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "List the functions of a Social Institution",
        answer: `
        I. They simplify behaviours for individuals  
        II. They provide ready-made forms of social relations and social roles.  
        III. They act as agencies of coordination and stability for total culture.  
        IV. They control behaviour`,
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "Examples of Social Institutions, include what ?",
        answer: "Family, Education, Religion, Politics, Economy, etc",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "What is Social Theory?",
        answer: "Social Theory is the study of scientific ways of thinking about life. It encompasses ideas about how the society changes and develop, about methods of explaining social behaviours.",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "What are the 3 BASIC theories used in explaining social institutions?",
        answer: `
        I. Structural Functionalities  
        II. Conflict Theories  
        III. Symbolic Interactionalism`,
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "Structural Functionalities and Conflict Theories are referred to as ",
        answer: "MACRO theories of the society",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "Symbolic Interactionalism is referred to as ",
        answer: "the MICRO theory of the society",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "Who proposed Functionalism? ",
        answer: "HERBERT SPENCER",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "Who opposed Functionalism? ",
        answer: "KARL MARX",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "Branches of Social Sciences includes what? ",
        answer: "Political Science, Economics, Psychology and Sociology",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "What is Political Science? ",
        answer: "Political Science refers to the characteristics and patterns of political systems, the principles and conducts of government, especially political parties, elections, system of government, foreign policy and the comparative study of government.",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "What is Economics? ",
        answer: "Economics is the study of the importance of production, distribution and consumption of goods and services. Other areas include :- pricing and marketing theories, consumer behaviour, etc. ",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "What is Psychology? ",
        answer: "Psychology is the study of an individual, his adjustment and personality, patterns of learning, motivation and perception.",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "What is Sociology? ",
        answer: "Sociology refers to the study of a group of people, their patterns of interaction, institutions and social organisations of the society.",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "What is the HIGHEST level of human development?",
        answer: "SOCIETY",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "Describe how (Ogundowole, 2004 page 31) explained Society",
        answer: "He explained social intercourse as the initial concept of socio-economic formation, which forms reciprocal process acting through the medium of two or more social factors within a framework of a single process under certain conditions of space and time.",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "Describe how Tonnies distinguished between a Society and Community",
        answer: "Tonnies stated that Community and Society are two types of human groupings, where Community is NATURAL and Society is ARTIFICIAL",
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "Differentiate between a Community and a Society ",
        answer: `
        I. Community is NATURAL and Society is ARTIFICIAL.   
        II. Community is a model of living organisms while Society is likened to a constructed machine or motor car.   
        III. In Community, the will is organic and spontaneous, while in the Society the will is a conscious decision from reflection. 
        IV. Community is based on tiles and communial life and is spiritual and unconscious while Society is based on a sudden agreement and collective emotion.  
        V. Community belongs to everyday life as depicted by the family while Society arises from exceptional cirumstances, like Friendships`,
        coursecode: 201
    },
    {
        question: "List and explain the groups of the Human Society",
        answer: `
        I. PRIMARY GROUP :- They are small and decimal, it may be a family, or ordinary unit. It may also include gangs and anti-social groups whose activities are usually disintegrating to the society.   
        II. SECONDARY GROUP :- They are usually dispersed in space and time and so large that they can't maintain close contact. This aggregate or individuals maybe association, parties, etc`,
        coursecode: 201
    }
]
